Tushar Gautam

Boulder, Colorado tushar.rishav@gmail.com

MS, Computer Science

LinkedIn @gautamtushar Github @tushar-rishav

SUMMARY

Proclivity towards problem-solving with over 5 years of full-stack product and platform development. At Anoki, I've led team building contextual video search product with TV Ads integration. Individual contributions included building full-stack product, design & develop scalable video stream processing, and setup reliable ML pipeline for processing large-scale datasets. Also, developed Recommendation System for TV channels, core platform libraries and various infrastructure setup.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer - Anoki Inc

Mountain View, CA, USA | June 2023 - Current

- Built full-stack contextual video search application, driving business revenues with TV Ads sales.
- Implemented processing several hundreds concurrent live TV channel streams with auto scale-out capabilities.
- Designed a reliable ML pipeline for deploying multi-modal model processing large-scale datasets distributed across GPU cluster.
- Developed recommendation system for consumer facing product, enhanced user experience with hyper-personalization of TV channels.
- Developed core platform libraries for Config Management and Service Discovery mechanisms based on Consul and Kubernetes.
- Implemented GraphQL backends for Content Management & Scheduling.
- Introductory discussions with team on Observability and best development practices.

Skills: Go, Python, TypeScript, Svelte/SvelteKit, Kubernetes, Metaflow, Airflow, Protobuf, gRPC, MySQL, MongoDB, Consul, Presto, Superset, HaProxy, GraphQL, Prometheus, Grafana and AWS - Mediaconvert, S3, Cloudfront, RDS, EKS.

Software Engineer Intern - PayPal

New York City, NY, USA | May 2022 - August 2022

· Added static type safety for GraphQL resolvers based on a schema-first design philosophy, increasing code maintainability.

Skills: TypeScript, GraphQL.

Software Engineer - LG Ads

Bangalore, KA, India | June 2017 — June 2021

- 5x latency optimization for a large-scale fingerprint distribution network for Audio Content Recognition system.
- Lead projects in the realm of core platform development with monitoring, logging and distributed storage infrastructure.
- Setup and managed key infrastructure projects: load balancers, and large-scale Spark cluster.

Skills: NodeJS, Python, Airflow, Bash, Docker, MySQL, HDFS, Ceph, Spark, Mesos, Kafka, Ansible, Jenkins, Prometheus, EtcD, HAProxy, Linux firewall.

Google Summer of Code - Python Software Foundation

Bangalore, KA, India | April 2016 - August 2016

- Built interactive static code analysis tool with 97% code coverage for frontend and, 100% for backend.
- Presented a workshop on "Guide to open-source contributions using Git and CI/CD" at EuroPython conference in Bilbao, Spain.

Skills: Python, AngularJS, HTML, CSS, Git, TravisCI, Docker, Karma, Mocha, ChaiJS, Test Driven Development.

PATENT

System For Contextual Searching Using Text Search Terms

Feb 2024

EDUCATION

M.S, University of Colorado, Boulder

Aug 2021 - May 2023

B.Tech, National Institute of Technology, Trichy

July 2013 - May 2017

RELEVANT COURSES

Advanced Data Structures and Algorithms, Network Systems, Operating Systems, Distributed Systems, NLP and Deep Learning, Database, Blockchain

PROJECTS

- Image Defogging using DDPM: A generative model leveraging U-Net and a linear noise scheduler to enhance the Foggy
 CityScapes dataset.

 May 2023
- Distributed Config Deployment: Implementation of fault-tolerant distributed system based on a spanning tree topology.
 [Github], [YouTube]
 Dec 2022
- Named Entity Recognition: Fine-tuned LLMs on a medical dataset achieving F1 score of 0.91.

Dec 2021

- SemEval-2022 Task-4: Detecting patronizing and condescending language with fine-tuning LLMs, ranked 1st. [Github] Dec 2021
- GitMate: Contributed bug fixes and new features for ranking bugs in GitMate an automated code review and issue triaging
 platform for GitHub projects.